

Daniel Byrd

Data Analyst, Programmer, Designer, Help Desk Analyst

Profile

Data Analyst/help desk analyst/programmer with 3 plus years of experience looking to utilize skills I have learned over the past several years to help others become more productive, enhance user experiences, and provide value to the business and their partners. I am a motivated self-starter, actively working to improve my skills and open to learning new technologies. You can view some the projects I have worked on in the past on my online portfolio found at:

https://mr-bland.github.io/Portfolio-DB/

Contact

PHONE:

864 363 7021

EMAIL:

daniel.byrd2@charter.net

LINKED-IN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-byrd-090004170/

LOCATION

Taylors, SC

Willing to work remote

Skills

Data Analyst

- Microsoft Excel
- Python
 - Libraries include: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Plotly, Dash, Wordcloud, BeautifulSoup
- SQL
- Power BI
- Looker Studio

Programmer Analyst

Help Desk Analyst

Education

<u>IBM Data Analyst Certification:</u> Completed certification course discussing and applying various technologies and methods for Data Analytics (2024)

<u>Greenville Technical College</u>: Associates degree in Computer Science (spring 2019)

<u>LinkedIn Learning</u>: Completed a number of technical courses.

<u>Bonds Career Center</u>: Technical training from 2015 to 2017

Work Experience

Service Desk Analyst at Pomeroy

(January 2020 – October 2023)

- Assisted UMB Bank with many technical issues from programs/systems not responding or operating correctly, to account unlocks and password resets. Completed a combined total of 12,000+ calls on various systems and issues.
- Constructed a HTML helper website designed to help format incident descriptions with preconfigured work notes for the most common issues. Also programed to have a separate page that allows the storage of the previously created incident descriptions.

Computer Programmer Intern at Budget Ninjas LLC

(July 2018 – October 2019) (Business Closed)

Technologies: Visual Studio, SQL, SSRS, ASP.NET, C#, Telerik, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Azure Devops

 Completed a number of projects to enhance their website and created an SSRS report for operations.

For more details please visit:

https://mr-bland.github.io/Portfolio